우드.
그들은 아주 먼 세상에서 왔습니다.
The Ood.
They came from a distant world.
그들은 별들 사이로 여행을 다녔습니다.
They voyaged across the stars.
하나의 목적을 위해서죠.
All with one purpose.
우유와 설탕을 드릴까요?
Do you take milk and sugar?
시중드는것!
-오, 좋군.
- To serve!
- Oh, that's good.
훌륭해. 마음에 드네, 선생.
That's excellent. I like it, sir.
당장 구입하겠어!
본론으로 들어가지!
Buy one now!
Direct, straight to the point!
2주동안 3개의 은하를 지나왔다고
말할것입니다. 그런다음 이렇게 소개합니다.
We play that across the Tri-Galactic
for two weeks, then introduce this.
50크레딧만 있으면 됩니다.
Now only 50 credits.
50? 우리가 50크레딧까지 가격을
내리기로 했던가?
50? We're reducing the
price to 50 credits?
판매가 저조합니다, 전략을 바꿔야 합니다.
계속 이렇게 가시죠.
Sales are down, we've got to
reposition ourselves. So get going.
바보같은! 피를 말려 죽일셈이군.
Idiot! Bleeding us dry.
거기 너, 지난달 군수출장부좀 가져와.
You there, get me last month's
military export figures.
육군들은 항상 보병들을 더 원한다니까.
The army always need more grunts.
알겠습니다.
Yes, sir.
바틀씨, 전화하라고 하셨다면서요?
Mr Bartle, you asked me to call you?
솔라나, 바이어들이 도착하면
우린 전엔 전혀 안해본것처럼 판매할거야.
Solana, when those buyers arrive, we
are going to pitch like never before.
난 저 우드들이 이곳에서 빨리 나갔으면 좋겠다고!
I want those Ood flying out of here!
이건...군수출장부를 가져오라고 했지,
이건 국내장부잖아.
That... I said military figures,
that's the domestic file.
군장부를 가져오란 말이야!
Get me the military!
그 파일은 무의미합니다.
The file is irrelevant, sir.
오, 그럼 이건 뭐야?
Oh, and why's that?
아악!
-좋은하루 되십시오.
- Aargh!
- Have a nice day!
한글자막-JIN. jhj124@naver.com(장혜진)
무단배포하지 말아주세요.
의역이나 오역이 있을수도 있습니다.
Doctor Who - 4x03
"우드의 행성"
"Planet of the Ood"
컨트롤을 랜덤으로 설정했어.
미스테리 관광인 셈이지!
Set the controls to random.
Mystery tour!
저 문밖은 아무 행성이나, 아무곳이나,
어떤 시간이나, 넓은 우주에 아무곳이나 될수있..
Outside that door
could be any planet, anywhere,
anywhen, in the whole, wide uni...
왜그래?
무서워서요.
I mean, history's one thing,
but an alien planet!
내말은, 역사는 하나의 사건이잖아요,
하지만 외계인 행성이라니!
말만하면 언제든지 집으로
데려다 줄수도 있어.
I could always take you home.
어이, 비웃지 말아요.
-어떤건지알아.
- Yeah, don't laugh at me.
- I know what it's like.
지금 당신이 느끼는 모든 감정들 말이야.
Everything you're feeling right now.
공포, 즐거움, 호기심.
나도 그래!
The fear, the joy, the wonder.
I get that.
정말로요? 그렇게 많이 돌아다녔는데?
Seriously? After all this time?
그래! 왜 내가 계속 여행을 다닌다고 생각하는거야?
Yeah! Why do you think I keep going?
오! 좋아요, 그럼. 우리 둘다 그래요!
Oh, all right then. You and me both.
미친거야!
This is barmy!
난 치스윅에서 태어났어요!
여행도 패키지여행밖에 안다녀봤는데!
I was born in Chiswick!
I've only ever done package holidays.
그런 내가 여기있다니! 이건...
Now I'm here! This is...
내 말은, 이건...
나도 모르겠어요, 이건 마치...
I mean it's...
I dunno, it's all sort of...
내가 말하고싶은 단어가 뭔지도 모르겠네!
I don't even know what the word is!
Oh, I've got the word.
오, 이제 어떤 단어인지 알겠네.
얼어죽겠어!
Freezing!
눈이잖아! 오, 진짜 눈이야.
Snow! Ah, real snow.
마침내 완전한 눈이군!
Proper snow at last!
바로이거야, 좋군!
어떻게 생각해?
That's more like it, lovely!
What do you think?
약간 추워요.
-전망좀 보라고!
- Bit cold.
- Look at that view!
그래요.
Yep.
아름답고, 추운 광경이네요.
Beautiful, cold view.
백만개의 은하의 백만개의 행성들중에
우리가 여기 온거야!
Millions of planets in millions
of galaxies, and we're on this one!
Multo bene! ('아주 좋아'라는 라틴어)
Bellissimo! ('매우 아름답다'라는 이탈리아어)
Multo bene! Bellissimo!
말해봐 도나. 치스윅에서 태어났지.
Says Donna. Born in Chiswick.
오, 일하고, 잠자고, 텔레비전에, 집세,
세금, 식당에서 사온 저녁.
당신은 이런 삶을 살았지.
Oh, you've had a life
of work and sleep...
...and telly, and rent
and tax and takeaway dinners.
모든 생일들과 크리스마스.
그리고 해마다 2주씩 주어지는 휴일.
하지만 끝내 당신은 이곳에 서 있잖아.
All birthdays and Christmases
and two weeks holiday a year.
And then you end up here.
지구의 일반인인 도나 노블이.
Donna Noble, citizen of the Earth.
다른 행성에 서있다!
Standing on a different planet!
어때, 도나?
How about that, Donna?
도나?
Donna?
미안해요, 뭐라고 했어요?
-그러면 좀 나아?
- Sorry, you were saying?
- Better?
좋아요, 고맙네요.
-편해?/-네.
- Lovely, thanks. Comfy?
- Yup.
그 안에 있으면 뭐가 들리긴 들려?
-뭐라고요?
- Can you hear anything inside that?
- Pardon?
좋아, 이렇게 말했지,
지구의 시민..
Right, I was saying,
citizen of the Earth.
A rocket!
로켓이다!
세상에, 정말, 진짜로 로켓이잖아!
Blimey, a real, proper rocket!
이제, 진짜 우주선이라고 부를게 생겼네요.
Now, that's what I call a spaceship.
당신은 박스를 가지고있고,
저 사람은 페라리를 가지고 있어요!
You've got a box,
he's got a Ferrari!
자요, 저 사람이 어디로 가는지 한번 보자고요.
Come on, let's see where he's going.
할펜씨, 우드 관리의 새 지휘자인
레이더 박사입니다.
Mr Halpen, sir.
Dr Ryder, new Head of Ood Management.
얼마나 죽었나? 말해보게,
정확한 사실을.
How many dead? Come on,
facts and figures.
나는 이 먼길을 이 얼어죽을 날씨에 대한
논의나 하자고 온게 아니네.
-솔라나가 수치를 가지고 있습니다.
I haven't flown all this way
to discuss the weather. Which is freezing.
Solana has the figures.
솔라나 머키리우스입니다. 마케팅과
은하계 교섭 담당입니다.
Solana Mercurio, sir. Head of
Marketing and Galactic Liaison.
내가 필요한건 수치를 가지고
있는 여자뿐이네.
Just what I need, a PR woman
난 내 말을 이렇게 자르는걸 좋아하지 않네.
알겠나?
I don't want a word of this
getting out, understand?
이제, 요점으로 돌아가지.
몇명이나 죽었나?
Now, get to the point.
How many dead?
과거에는 금융관계자의 1/4.
총 3명이 죽었습니다.
In the past financial quarter, we've
had three deaths in the complex.
모두 심장 발작이나 산업상의 사고라고
여겼었습니다만..
All attributed to heart attacks
or industrial accidents.
이 테이프를 얻고난뒤, 모든 원인은
같은것으로 보여집니다.
But now we've captured this on tape,
the cause would seem the same.
통역구를 무기처럼 쓰는군.
어떻게 작동하는건가?
It's using the translator ball
as a weapon. How's that work?
잘 모르겠습니다. 장치를 체크해봤지만,
아무것도 나오지 않습니다.
I've no idea. I'm checking
the equipment, nothing so far.
이 각도에서는 우드의 눈이 보이지 않는군.
Can't see its eyes from this angle.
아마도 추측해야 할것...
I think we have to assume...
레드아이.
-저도 그렇게 생각했습니다.
- Red-eye.
- I would think so, sir.
저 우드는 어떻게 됐나?
That Ood, what happened to it?
거칠게 도망갔습니다. 개처럼요.
Ran for the wilds, sir, like a dog.
경비대중 한명이 발포했습니다.
아마 지금쯤이면 죽었을겁니다.
One of the guards fired off a shot,
it'll be dead by now.
레드아이가 뭔지 물어봐도 되겠습니까?
Can I ask, what's red-eye, sir?
그게, 감염의 일종이야.
말 그대로 우드의 눈이 색깔이 바뀌는거지.
Some sort of infection.
The Ood eyes literally change colour.
마실거!
-원인을 알아낼수가 없습니다.
모든 박테리아 스캔에도 음성으로 나옵니다.
Drink! I can't find the source,
all the bacterial scans
register negative.
죄송합니다만, 할펜씨께서 세우신 규칙에 의하면
기본적으로 여기선 술이 금지되어있습니다.
I'm sorry, but according
to your own rules, sir,
there's no alcohol allowed on base.
자네가 굳이 알아야 한다면
이건 헤어토닉이네.(대머리 치료제)
It's hair tonic, if you must know.
5년전엔 나도 머리카락이 많았는데 말이지.
Five years ago,
I had a full head of hair.
스트레스! 이게 다 스트레스 때문이야!
Stress, that's what this is, stress!
[THEY LAUGH]
[EERIE SINGING]
Hold on, can you hear that?
잠깐, 저거 들려?
도나, 모자 벗어.
저 소리, 노래같은데.
That noise, it's like a song.
저기야!
Over there!
뭐에요?
What is it?
우드. 그는 우드라고 불려.
An Ood. He's called an Ood.
하지만 그건 얼굴이..
But its face...
도나, 그러지마. 지금은 아니야.
이자는 '그'야. '그게'아니라고. 좀 도와줘.
Donna, don't. Not now.
It's a he, not an it. Give me a hand.
미안해요!
Sorry!
심장이 어디있는지 모르겠어.
그에게 심장이 '있는지도' 모르겠어.
I don't know where the heart is.
I don't know if he's GOT a heart.
그에게 계속 말걸어.
Talk to him, keep him going.
괜찮아요. 우리가 돌봐줄께요.
It's all right, we've got you.
음, 이름이 뭐에요?
Um, what's your name?
델타 50 이라고 지정된 우드입니다.
Designated Ood
Delta 50.
내 이름은 도나에요.
My name's Donna.
아니, 아니, 아니, 아니야.
당신은 그거 필요없어.
No, no, no, no. You don't need to...
미안해요.
Sorry.
오, 세상에! 이 사람은 닥터에요.
Oh, God! This is the Doctor!
딱 당신에게 필요한거죠. 의사요.
이보다 더 좋을순 없죠, 네?
Just what you need, a doctor.
Couldn't be better, eh?
총에 맞았군.
You've been shot.
그 원...
-아니, 무리하지 말아요.
The circle... No, don't try to talk.
원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다.
The circle must be broken.
원이라니? 무슨뜻이야?
델타 50, 무슨 원?
Circle? What do you mean?
Delta 50, what circle?
델타 50, 무슨 원?
으악!
Aargh!
죽었어요.
He's gone.
조심해.
Careful.
불쌍하게도..
There you are, sweetheart.
우리가 너무 늦었어요. 우리가 무엇을 하면
좋을까요, 그를 묻어줄까요? 아니면...
We were too late. What do we do,
do we bury him or...?
눈이 덮어줄거야.
The snow will take care of that.
그는 누구였죠? 우드는 또 뭐고요?
Who was he? What's an Ood?
그들은 42세기 인간들의 하인이야.
They're servants,
of humans in the 42nd century.
정신력 텔레파시, 그건 노래였어.
Mildly telepathic, that was the song.
누군가를 부르는 그의 마음이었지.
It was his mind calling out.
아무것도 못들었어요.
Couldn't hear anything.
그는 죽어가면서도 노래를 부른거군요.
He sang as he was dying.
그의 눈이 빨갛게 변했어.
-그게 무슨 의미인데요?
- His eyes turned red.
- What's that mean?
문제가 생겼다는 의미지. 가자.
Trouble. Come on.
우드는 위험하지 않아.
완전히 온화한 종족이라고.
The Ood are harmless.
They're completely benign.
내가 그들을 마지막으로 만났을때만 빼고.
그때는 어떤 힘이 있었어.
Except, the last time I met them,
there was this force,
저들을 끝내버리기에 충분히 강력한
정신력 같은거였지.
like a stronger mind,
powerful enough to take them over.
무슨 힘인데요?
-얘기하자면 길어.
- What sort of force?
- Long story.
걸어갈 길도 길어요.
-악마였어.
- Long walk.
- It was the Devil.
만약 당신이 그 악마를 데리고 다녔다면
당장에 내 후드로 덮어버렸을 텐데..
If you're gonna take the mickey,
I'll just put my hood back up.
이번엔 틀림없이 뭔가가 달라.
Must be something different
this time, though.
뭔가 집같은것에 가까워 지는데.
Something closer to home.
아하!
A-ha!
도시야!
Civilisation!
신사 숙녀 여러분,
우드-천체에 온것을 환영합니다.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the Ood-Sphere.
상쾌하지 않나요? 여기 안내책자가 있습니다.
증표, 3D 티켓과 단지의 지도를 받으세요.
And isn't it bracing?
Here are your information packs,
with vouchers, 3D tickets
and a map of the complex.
제 이름은 솔라나 입니다. 마케팅 담당이죠.
모두 비드폰을통해 말하게 될것입니다.
My name's Solana,
Head of Marketing.
I'm sure we've all spoken
on the vidfone.
그럼 이제 절 따라와주세요.
-미안, 미안, 미안해요! 늦었어요.
- Now, if you'd like to follow me.
- Sorry, sorry, sorry! Late.
우리는 신경쓰지말아요. 안녕하세요!
경비대가 지나가게 해줬어요.
Don't mind us. Hello!
The guards let us through.
그럼 당신들은..?
-닥터하고 도나 노블이에요.
And you would be?
The Doctor and Donna Noble.
은하계 우주간의 PLC(Public Limited
Company)에 입법한 노블 단체의 대표죠.
Representing the Noble Corporation
PLC Limited, Intergalactic.
제 명단에서 빠졌나 보군요. 죄송합니다.
다시는 이런일 없을겁니다.
Must have fallen off my list,
my apologies. Won't happen again.
그럼, 노블 박사님, 노블 부인,
괜찮으시다면 저와 함께 가시죠.
Now then, Dr Noble, Mrs Noble,
if you'd like to come with me.
오, 아니, 아니, 우리는 결혼한게 아니에요!
-우리는 절대 결혼한게 아니에요.
-절대로요.
Oh, no, no, we're not married!
- We're so not married. - Never.
절대 그럴일 없어요!
-알겠습니다.
- Never ever!
- Of course.
안내책자 받으세요, 증표는 안에 있습니다.
And here are your information
packs, vouchers inside.
이제 저를 따라오세요,
안은 따뜻하고 멋지답니다.
Now if you'd like to come with me,
the Executive Suites are nice and warm.
저게 뭐지? 비상경보기 소리같은데.
[ALARM WAILS]
What's that? Sounds like an alarm.
이런 제길, 바이어들이 도착했을텐데,
누가 비상경보기를 울린거야? 마실거!
For God's sake, we've got the buyers
arriving, who sounded the alarm? Drink!
Oh, it's just a siren
for the end of the work shift.
오, 이건 작업 교대를 위한 사이렌소리일 뿐입니다.
자, 이쪽입니다, 될수있는대로 빨리 오세요!
Now then, this way,
quick as you can!
케스, 대체 무슨일이 벌어지고 있는겐가?
-우드가 풀려났습니다.
- Mr Kess, what the hell's going on?
- Ood on the loose, sir.
저희가 잡았던 저번것과 비슷합니다.
-레드아이? /-그런것같습니다.
Looks like we've got another one.
- Red-eye? - As red as sin, sir.
걱정마십쇼, 할펜시. 저희가 잡겠습니다.
Don't worry, Mr Halpen, we're on it.
저깄습니다!
Sir!
좋아, 제군들! 가서 잡아!
All right then, lads - go, get him!
보시다시피, 우드는 시중을 들면서
행복해합니다.
As you can see, the Ood are happy
to serve, and we keep them in
facilities of the highest standard.
그리고 저희는 우드를 높은 수준의
시설에서 관리하고있습니다.
여기있는 '더블 O'는
우드 관리에대한 것으로,
Here at the Double O
that's Ood Operations
we like to think
of the Ood as our trusted friends.
저희는 우드를 우리의 좋은 친구라고
생각하고 있습니다.
저쪽으로! 너희 둘은 나를 따라오고!
Over there. You two follow me.
저희는 우드를 건강하고 안전하게
관리하고 교육시킵니다.
We keep the Ood healthy,
safe, and educated.
생포해!
Take him alive!
저희는 단지 우드를 기르는것이 아닙니다.
We don't just breed the Ood.
그들을 더 좋은 종으로 만드는 것이죠.
We make them better.
우드는 무엇일까요?
바로 우리의 거울이 아닐까요?
but a reflection of us?
만일 당신의 우드가 행복하다면
If your Ood is happy...
크아악!
Aaargh!
..그렇다면 당신도 행복해질것입니다.
..then you'll be happy, too.
할펜씨, 다른 우드보다 눈이
빨간정도가 심합니다.
Mr Halpen, this is a bit more
than red-eye, sir.
뭔가 새로운겁니다.
This is something new,
미쳤습니다.
-크아악!
it's rabid, sir.
레이더 박사를 데려오게.
Take it to Dr Ryder.
그냥, 안보이는곳으로 치워버려!
Just get it out of sight!
그래, 그래, 그래.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
어떤것같아? 다시 자라고 있는것 같나?
What do you think?
Growing back?
조금이라도?
Just a little bit?
그럴줄 알았어!
Like you'd know!
이제 논점에서 벗어나 우드 관리에서의
새로운 기술혁신에대해 설명드리겠습니다.
I'd now like to point out a new
innovation from Ood Operations.
우드 통역구와 함께 여러가지 패키지를
설명해드리겠습니다.
We've introduced a variety package
with the Ood translator ball.
기본 세팅부터 보시겠습니다.
You can now have
the Standard Setting.
오늘 어때? 우드?
How are you today, Ood?
아주 좋습니다. 감사합니다.
I'm perfectly well,
thank you.
또는 스트레스 쌓인날, 신사분들을
위한 작은 서비스도 준비되어 있습니다.
Or perhaps, after a stressful day, a
little something for the gentlemen.
어때? 우드?
And how are you, Ood?
당신을 보니 모든것이 좋아집니다.
[SULTRY FEMALE VOICE]
All the better for seeing you.
그리고 고전 코미디 옵션도 있습니다.
우드, 너 뭔가를 떨어뜨렸어.
And the comedy classic option.
Ood, you dropped something.
D'oh! (심슨가족에 나오는
'제길'같은 감탄사)
D'oh!
이 모든게 5크레딧만 추가하시면
이용하실수 있습니다.
All that for only five
additional credits.
자세한건 팜플렛에 나와있습니다.
The details are in your brochures.
많은 음식과 마실것이 준비되어 있으니
그냥 가지 마시고 즐기다 가세요.
Now, there's plenty more food
and drink, so, don't hold back.
오, 됐군!
Ah, got it!
우드-천체, 나 몇년전에
이 태양계에 와본적있어.
The Ood-Sphere, I've been to this
solar system before, years ago, ages!
아니, 몇세기전에!
센스-천체 행성에 가까이 있어.
Close to the planet Sense-Sphere.
넓혀볼까.
Widen out.
4126년이야. 인간 제국의 가장 위대하고
윤택한 2번째 번영기지.
The year 4126. That is the Second
Great and Bountiful Human Empire.
4126년이라니..
4126.
4126년이라고 한거죠?
It's 4126.
내가 4126년에 있다니.
-좋지, 안그래?
- I'm in 4126.
- It's good, isn't it?
지금의 지구는 어때요?
What's the Earth like now?
인구가 좀 많아. 하지만 제국은 3개의
은하를 가로질러 뻗어있지.
Bit full. But you see, the Empire
stretches out across three galaxies.
이상해요.
내 말은, 훌륭해요, 하지만...
It's weird.
I mean, it's brilliant, but...
집으로 돌아가면 신문과 텔레비전에선
여전히 인간이 오래살지 못할거라고 떠들어댈거 아니에요.
Back home, the papers and the telly
keep saying we haven't got long to live.
지구온난화나, 홍수.
Global warming. Flooding.
벌들이 사라진거나, 그런거 말이에요.
All the bees disappearing.
- Yeah,
그래, 벌에관한건 좀 이상하다.
that thing about the bees is odd.
하지만 우릴 좀 봐요!
인간들은 어디에나 있어요.
But look at us!
We're everywhere.
하지만 이게 좋은건가요, 나쁜건가요?
우리는 탐험가같은건가요?
Is that good or bad, though?
Are we like explorers?
아니면 좀 더 바이러스같은건가?
-나도 가끔은 그게 궁금해.
- Or more like a virus?
- Sometimes I wonder.
저 빨간 점들은 뭐에요?
What are the red dots?
우드들이 집중적으로 분포되어있는 곳이야.
Ood distribution centres.
세 은하계를 가로질러서요?
Across three galaxies?
우드한테 한번 물어볼까?
Don't the Ood get a say in this?
음, 미안한데, 잠깐만요...
Um, sorry, but...
안녕하세요. 당신들은 다 이런상태인가요?
Hello. Tell me,
are you ALL like this?
질문을 이해 못하겠습니다. 아가씨.
I do not understand, Miss.
왜 내게 '아가씨'라고 하는거죠?
내가 싱글로 보이나요?
Why do you say "Miss",
do I look single?
논점으로 돌아가.
-그래요.
- Back to the point.
- Yeah.
내 말이 무슨 뜻이냐면요,
자유로운 우드는 없나요?
What I mean is,
are there any free Ood?
야생동물처럼 들판을
달리는 우드는 없어요?
Are there Ood running wild
somewhere? Like wildebeest.
모든 우드는 시중을 들기위해 태어납니다.
All Ood are born to serve.
그러지 않으면, 저희는 죽게됩니다.
Otherwise, we would die.
하지만 꼭 그렇게 시작할 필요는 없잖아요.
But you can't have
started like that.
인간들이 오기전엔 어땠나요?
-원.
Before the humans,
what were you like? - The circle.
무슨뜻이야? 무슨 원?
What do you mean,
what circle?
원, 그 원은...원은...
The circle, the circle is...
여러분! 그리고 모든 우드들은
접대실로 자리를 옮겨주세요.
Ladies and gentlemen! All Ood
to Hospitality Stations, please.
수다떨시간은 충분히 있는데.
I've had enough of the schmoozing.
정해진 길에서 조금 벗어나보는거 좋아해?
-소개해 드리겠...
Do you fancy going off the beaten
track? - If I can introduce you...
Rough Guide to the Ood-Sphere?
우드-천체의 형편없는 가이드씨?
안내해줄래요? / -그러죠.
What the hell
is wrong with it?
도대체 뭐가 문젠건가?
이건 분명 레드-아이의 두번째 단계인듯합니다.
It's obviously stage two of red-eye.
그게 무엇이든지 말이죠.
Whatever that means.
우드 시그마, 전에 이런걸 본적이 있나?
Ood Sigma, have you
seen this before?
인류가 저희를 정의내립니다.
Humanity defines us, sir.
저희들은 인류에게서 답을 찾습니다.
We look to you for answers.
둘다 퍽도 도움이 되는군.
Fat lot of good, all of you.
우리는 수십만의 우드를 모든 개화된
행성에 수출하고 있네.
We're exporting hundreds
of thousands of Ood
to all the civilised planets.
만약 우드들이 미쳐날뛴다면,
그게 무엇을 뜻하는지는 자네도 알고있겠지.
If they turn rabid,
you know what it'll mean.
이제 방법은 오직 하나뿐입니다. 15번 창고를 확인하게 해주십쇼.
There's only one thing
I haven't checked, sir. Warehouse 15.
왜 15번 창고가 문제의 원인이라고
생각하는거지? 벌써 2세기나 지났잖나.
변한건 아무것도 없어. 마실거!
Why should that cause trouble?
It's been two centuries now.
저도 그곳이 접근이 제한되어 있다는건
잘 알지만 이 일을 해결하기위해선 제가
꼭 들어가 봐야합니다. 이런 상황에서는요.
I know it's restricted access,
but if I'm going to work on this,
I should see it.
Just in case.
어쩔수 없군.
Can't stand the place.
그럼, 15번 창고로 가보지. 따라오게.
Still. Warehouse 15 then, come on.
이건 어쩌고요?
What about this one, sir?
글쎄, 부검용으로 하면 좋겠지.
Well, I'd suggest a post mortem.
그러니까, 먼저 죽인다음에 말일세.
Which means it's
got to be dead first.
[GUNFIRE]
'우드는 지금 당장 8번구역으로 이동한다.'
'Ood shift eight, now commencing.
'반복한다, 우드는 지금 당장
8번구역으로 이동한다.'
'Repeat,
Ood shift eight now commencing.'
일어나! 일어나라고 했지!
Get up! I said get up!
하인이라고요? 저건 완전 노예잖아요.
Servants? They're slaves.
일어나!
Get up!
전진!
March!
지난번에 우드를 만났을때 난 이런건
생각도 못했어. 질문조차 하지 않았지.
-당신답지 않네요. / -내가 좀 바빴거든.
Last time I met the Ood,
I never thought. I never asked.
- That's not like you.
- I was busy.
너무 바빠서 그들을 구할수가 없었어.
우드들이 죽도록 그냥 내버려뒀지.
난 저들에게 빛이 하나 있는거야.
So busy I couldn't save them,
I had to let the Ood die.
I reckon I owe them one.
저 사람이 사장같은데요. -어디로 가는지 보자. 가자.
- That looks like the boss.
- Let's keep out of his way. Come on.
How long since you went inside?
마지막으로 들어가본지 얼마나 되셨죠?
Must be... ten years ago.
아마...10년전일걸세.
'15번 창고입니다.'
-아버지께선 내가 6살때
나를 이곳에 데려오셨었지.
'Warehouse 15.' - My father brought
me here, when I was six years old.
'보안 프로토콜이 시작됩니다.'
냄새한번 죽이는군.
'Security protocol initiated.'
- God, the stench of it.
'15번 창고, 문 개방합니다.'
'Warehouse 15. Door open.'
[ELECTRICAL CRACKLING]
믿을수 없어.
Incredible.
내가 말했듯이, 변한건 없네.
Like I said.
Nothing's changed.
문서를 읽어본적은 있습니다. 하지만...
완전히 준비된건 아니군요.
I've read the documents, but...
it doesn't quite prepare you.
저게 나를 보고있는건가, 아니면
단지 그렇게 느껴지는것뿐인가?
Is it just me, or does it feel
as if it's looking at you?
제 생각엔 베리어기계가 잘만 돌아간다면
알아낼수 있을것 같습니다.
I think I understand
the barrier mechanics well enough.
신호를 확인해보겠습니다.
I'll check the signal.
Suppose it's home sweet home to you.
What d'you think?
만약 저게 너에게 소중하고 아늑한
집 이라고 가정한다면 어떨것같나?
전 의견이 없습니다. -그렇겠지...
- I have no opinion, sir.
- Well...
아빠에게 안녕이라고 말해봐라.
say hello to Daddy.
손상된곳은 없습니다. 베리어는 그대로
입니다. 비정상적인 신호도 200년전과
똑같습니다.
Nothing. The barrier's intact.
No abnormal signal.
Same as it's been for 200 years.
할펜씨, 노블단체에서 온 두 사람이 보안 체크를 통과하는데 실패했습니다.
'Mr Halpen, the two people from the
Noble Corporation failed to pass
security checks.
노블 단체라는 회사는 없습니다.
그런 회사는 존재하지 않습니다.
There's no such company,
the Noble Corporation doesn't exist.
게다가 그들이 사라졌습니다.
And on top of that, they seem
to have gone missing, sir,
'닥터와 노블이란 여자입니다.'
'the Doctor and Miss Noble.'
당장 해야할일은 그들을 찾아내는거야.
비상경보기는 울리지 말고, 알아들었어?
Just what I need
Start a search, no alarms, got that?
조용히 처리해.
Keep it quiet.
봤지? 이래서 머리가 빠지는거야. 마실거!
You see? Hair loss! Drink!
대화를 해보자고, 오랜친구여.
이건 내가 내지.
Tell you what, old friend.
Have this one on me.
건배!
Cheers!
[LOUD RUMBLE]
아무래도 이쯤에서 끝내야 할것같구만.
I think we're finished here.
미안.
Sorry.
[ELECTRICAL CRACKLING]
[PIERCING WHISTLE]
휘파람부는건 어디서 배운거야?
-매주 토요일마다 웨스트 햄에서 배웠어요.
- Where d'you learn to whistle?
- West Ham, every Saturday.
우드를 수출하는 곳이야.
Ood export.
보여?
컨테이너를 들어올려서,
D'you see?
Lifts up the containers,
로켓 화물창고에 넣은다음, 날려보낼 준비를 하는거야.
takes them to the rocket sheds,
ready to be flown out,
3개의 은하계로.
all over the three galaxies...
아니, 지금 그 말은, 저 컨테이너들이 모두 우드들로..?
What, you mean,
these containers are full of..?
어떻게 생각해?
What d'you think?
오, 역겨워요!
Ohhh, it stinks!
컨테이너 하나당 우드들이 몇명이나 들어있을것같아요?
How many of them
do you think there are in each one?
백명정도? 아님 그보다 더? -이 훌륭하고 거대한 제국은 노예들에
의해 지어진거군요.
A hundred? More?
A great big
empire, built on slavery.
그건 당신이 살던 시대와 다르지 않지.
-어이, 난 노예같은거 없어요!
It's not so different from your
time. - Oy! I haven't got slaves!
당신 옷은 누가 만든거라고 생각해?
Who d'you think made your clothes?
Is that why you travel
round with a human
그게 당신이 당신 옆에 인간을 데리고
다니며 여행을 하는 이유인가요?
at your side? It's not so you can
show them the wonders
of the universe,
우주의 신비함을 보여주는게 아니라,
치사하게 공격하려고?
it's so you can take cheap shots?
미안해. -알면 됐어요.
- Sorry.
- Well, don't.
우주인씨.
Space Man.
이해가 안가요, 문은 열려있잖아요.
왜 당신들은 도망가지 않는거죠?
I don't understand, the door was
open, why don't you just run away?
왜 도망을 가야 하죠?
- For what reason? - You could be free.
- I do not understand the concept.
그러면 당신은 자유로워 질 수 있으니까요.
-개념을 이해하지 못하겠습니다.
저 구가 뭐길래 계속 가지고 다니는거죠?
What is it with that Persil ball?
내 말은, 저들이 저 구와 함께 태어난건
아닐거 아니에요, 안그래요? 근데 왜 다들
저 구를 달고다니는거에요?
I mean, they're not born with it,
are they?
Why do they have to be
all plugged in?
우드, 말해봐. '원' 이라는게
너희들에게 무슨 의미지?
Ood, tell me, does 'the circle'
mean anything to you?
원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다.
ALL: The circle must be broken.
우와, 이거 소름끼치는데?
Woah, that is creepy!
그게 뭔데? 원이라는게 뭐냐고?
-원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다.
- But what is it? What is the circle?
- The circle must be broken.
어째서?
Why?
그래야 우리가 노래를 할 수 있으니까.
So that we can sing.
할펜씨? 여기는 우드 화물칸입니다. 불청객들을 찾았습니다. 잡아!
Mr Halpen? I'm in Ood Cargo,
I've found your unwanted guests. Go!
오, 아마 우릴 잡으러 오는것같아! 가자!
[ALARM WAILS]
Oh, I think that's us! Come on!
비상경보기 꺼!
비상경보기는 안된다고 했잖아!
Cut the alarms! I said, no alarms!
여러분, 걱정하실거 없습니다.
그냥 화재 대피 훈련일 뿐입니다.
Nothing to worry about, ladies and
gentlemen, it's just a fire drill.
저희는 항상 이시간에 이 시스템을
점검합니다. 잠깐 실례하겠습니다.
We test the system at this time
every day. If you'll excuse me.
닥터! 여기 문이 있어요!
Doctor, there's a door!
움직이지마!
-어디간거야?
-꼼짝말고 있어!
- Don't move... - Where've you gone?
- stay where you are.
놔줘! 이거 놔!
Get off me! Get off me!
도나! 어딨어?!
Donna! Where are you?
모든 경비대는 철수한다.
-'예?'
철수하라고 했다.
All guards withdraw. 'Sir?'
I said withdraw.
주변에 대기시켜라.
나머지 한명은 내가 잡겠다.
Keep to the perimeter.
I've got this one.
난 항상 이게 한번쯤 해보고 싶었지.
I've always wanted to do this.
컨테이너는 잠겼다.
Container locked. Ahh!
나 좀 도와줄래요?
Can you help me?
오, 안돼, 그러지마!
Oh, no, you don't!
내가 뭘 했다고? 난 저들과 달라!
난 너희들 편이야!
What have I done? I'm not one
of that lot. I'm on YOUR side!
움직이지 말고 가만히 있어!
명령이야!
Just stay where you are.
That's an order.
가만히 있으라고 했잖아! 닥터! 닥터!!!
I said, stay! Doctor! Doctor...!
지시를 들으셨을텐데요.
할펜씨는 저들을 생포하길 원하십니다.
You heard the instructions.
Mr Halpen wants them alive.
닥터, 꺼내줘요!
Doctor, get me out!
닥터, 여기서 날 꺼내줘요!
Doctor, get me out of here!
저 소릴 들으니 큰 위험에 빠진것같은데.
나 말고, 저 안에 있는 여자.
-컨테이너를 열어라!
Not from me, from her.
Unlock the container!
닥터!
-여기 있었군, 안전해 보이네.
- Doctor!
- There we go, safe and sound.
난 신경쓰지말고 저들이나
어떻게 좀 해봐요!
Never mind about me,
what about them?!
아아악!
적색경보! 발포하라!
Red alert! Fire!
쏴서 죽여!
Shoot to kill!
만약 사람들이 지구로 돌아가면...
여기서 무슨일이 벌어졌는지 알게되겠네요.
If people back on Earth...
- knew what was going on here...
- Oh, don't be so stupid.
오, 어리석게 굴지 말아요.
당연히 알죠.
Of course they know.
-They know how you treat the Ood?
-They don't ask. Same thing.
그들은 당신들이 우드를 어떻게
관리하는지 아나요?
-그런건 안물어봐요. 똑같아요.
솔라나, 우드는 이런식으로 태어나는게
아니에요. 봉사를 위해 태어난 종들은
애당초 절대 진화할수 없어요.
The Ood aren't born like this.
A species born to serve could never
evolve in the first place.
회사가 그들을 복종하게
만들기위해 뭘 한거에요?
What does the company
do to make them obey?
- That's nothing to do with me!
- What, cos you don't ask?
나는 그런거 몰라요!
-왜요, 안물어봤으니까?
그건 레이더 박사님 담당이에요. -그 사람, 어디있어요?
단지의 어느쪽에 있어요?
- That's Dr Ryder's territory. - And
where's he? What part of the complex?
내가 도울수 있어요, 레드-아이도 내가
해결할수 있어요, 그러니, 어서 알려줘요!
I could help,
with the red-eye, now show me!
저기에요. 적색 영역 넘어서요.
- There... Beyond the red section.
- Come with me.
나랑 같이 갑시다.
당신도 창고에서 다 봤잖아요,
You've seen the warehouse,
you can't agree with all this.
당신도 그 모든것에 동의할수는 없을거 아니에요.
당신은 나보다 이곳을 잘 아니까 도와줘요.
You know this place better than me,
you could help.
여기에요! 침입자들이 여기있어요!
경비대! 여기에요!
[SHE SHOUTS] They're over here!
Guards! They're over here!
남자와 여자 용의자가 달아났습니다.
Male and female suspects escaped.
Wasteridge corridor.
할펜씨, 닥터를 찾았습니다.
그는 우드 변환실로 가고있습니다.
Mr Halpen, I found the Doctor.
He's heading for Ood Conversion.
'그리로 가지.'
케스, 지금 상황은 어떤가?
'On my way.'
Mr Kess, what's the situation?
제압했습니다. 울타리 안에
가두어 놓았습니다.
We've contained it, sir, fenced them
in. But the red eye seems to be
permanent this time, it's not fading.
하지만 이번 레드-아이는 영구적인것
같습니다. 사라지지 않습니다.
그보다 안좋은건...우드들이 점점 더
미쳐가고 있다는 것입니다.
Worse than that, sir...
there's more of them going rabid.
제 의견을 말하자면, 아마 우드들을
포기해야 할 것 같습니다.
모두 오염됐습니다.
My opinion, sir, I think we've lost
them. The entire batch, contaminated.
원인이 뭐야? 왜 하필 지금이냐고?
뭐가 우드를 변화시킨거지?
What's causing it?
Why now? What's changed?
우드가 총 얼마나 되나?
-약 2000정도 입니다.
- How many Ood, in total?
- I'd say about 2,000, sir.
'포기하도록 하지,
그게 최선의 대비책이야.'
'We can write them off,
that's what insurance is for.'
마실거! 우리에게 사육장은 많이
있으니, 다시 시작하면 돼.
Drink! We've plenty more on the
Breeding Farms, let's start again.
산탄을 가져오게. (포탄같은것)
'멸살시켜버려.'
Fetch the canisters.
'No survivors.'
알겠습니다.
산탄가져와!
My pleasure, sir.
You lot - canisters!
이쪽이야!
Oh, can you hear it?
오, 저거 들려?
I didn't need the map,
I should've listened.
지도같은건 필요없어,
난 그냥 듣기만 하면 되는거야.
잠깐만요. 그러면 우리가 갇히는 꼴이 되잖아요?
-들어봐.
Hold on. Does that mean
we're locked in? - Listen.
들어봐, 들어봐, 들어봐, 들어봐...
Listen, listen, listen, listen...
[EERIE SINGING]
오, 머리야!
Oh, my head!
왜그래요?
-저거 안들려?
- What is it?
- Can't you hear it?
노래말이야.
The singing?
[THEY SING]
They look different to the others.
저들은 다른 우드들과 다른것같아요.
That's because they're
natural-born Ood, unprocessed,
왜냐면 저들은 가공되지 않은
자연그대로 태어난 우드이기 때문이야.
저들이 노예로 개조되기 전인 상태인거야. 망쳐지지 않은 상태.
before they're adapted to slavery.
Unspoilt.
[SINGING CONTINUES]
이건 그들의 노래야. -난 아무것도 안들려요.
- That's their song.
- I can't hear it.
D'you want to?
듣고싶어?
Yeah.
네.
이건 포로의 노래야.
-듣게해줘요.
It's the song of captivity.
Let me hear it.
날 봐.
Face me.
마음을 열어, 그렇지.
Open your mind, that's it.
[CLEAR, SAD SINGING]
Hear it, Donna.
들어봐, 도나.
Hear the music. Oh...!
노래를 들어봐. -오...!
[SINGING CONTINUES]
멈춰줘요.
Take it away.
그러고 싶어?
You sure?
못 견디겠어요.
I can't bear it.
미안해요.
I'm sorry.
괜찮아.
That's OK.
But you can still hear it?
하지만 당신은 여전히 들리는거죠?
항상 들려.
All the time.
이봐, 왜 이렇게 꾸물거리는거야?
-실험실, 최대 보안 시스템, 그자가
모든 시스템을 녹여버렸습니다.
What's the hold-up?
It's the experimentation lab,
maximum security, he's fused the system.
그냥 서 있지만 말고 볼트커터기를 가져다가 저 문을 찢어버려!
Don't just stand there, get the
bolt-cutters, rip that door off!
Solana, go back to the reps,
솔라나 접대실로 돌아가,
난 바이어들중 어느 누구도 어디론가
사라지거나 이 상황을 보는걸 원하지 않아.
I don't want any of them
wandering off and seeing this.
And get them away
from the Ood, just in case.
그리고 바이어들을 우드들에게서
멀리 떨어트려놔. 만일을 대비해서.
Hurry up!
- Yes, sir.
얼른! -알겠습니다.
[METALLIC THUD]
They're breaking in.
저들이 문을 부수고 들어왔나봐요.
아, 신경쓰지마.
Ah, let them.
뭘 쥐고 있는거야? 보여줘.
What are you holding? Show me.
친구.
Friend.
닥터, 도나, 친구.
Doctor. Donna. Friend.
좀 보자...나 좀 봐봐.
Let me see... Look at me...
좀 보여줘.
Let me see.
그렇지. 그렇지, 그래. 그래...
That's it. That's it, go on. Go on...
저건...?
Is that...?
이건 뇌야. 후뇌지.
It's a brain. A hind brain.
우드는 제 2의 뇌를 갖고 태어나는거야.
인간의 편도처럼. (대뇌의 한 부분)
The Ood are born with a secondary
brain. Like the amygdala in humans,
그건 기억과 감정을 가공하는 역할을해.
그게 없으면 당신은 더이상 도나가
아니야. 우드랑 같게되지.
it processes memory and emotions.
Get rid of that and you wouldn't be
Donna any more. You'd be like an Ood,
가공된 우드 말이야.
-그럼 회사가 한짓이...
우드들의 뇌를 잘라낸거에요?
a processed Ood. So the company...
cuts off their brains?
게다가 그들은 번역기에 매어놓기까지 했지.
And they stitch on the translator.
전두엽 백질 절제술처럼요.
Like a lobotomy.
I spent all that time
looking for you, Doctor,
난 당신을 찾아다니는데에 모든 시간을 보냈었어요, 닥터.
왜냐면 밖은 굉장히 아름다울거라고 생각했었거든요.
because I thought it would be
so wonderful out here.
이젠 집으로 가고싶어요.
I want to go home.
[THUD]
저들이 우드와 함께있습니다.
- They're with the Ood, sir.
- What you gonna do, then? Arrest me?
어쩔꺼야? 날 체포할건가?
감금시킬거야? 우리안으로 던져버릴건가?
글쎄, 이미 늦었어! 하!
Lock me up? Throw me in a cage?
Well, you're too late! Hah!
왜 그냥 나와서 행동주의자라고 말하지 않았나?
Why don't you just come out
and say it? FOTO activists!
만약 그게 우드의 친구라는걸 증명하기
위한 거라면, 맞아!
-우드는 우리없인 아무것도 아니야,
If that's what Friends Of The Ood
are trying to prove, yes!
The Ood were nothing without us,
그냥 얼음위를 배회하는 동물일 뿐이라고.
-그것때문에 넌 그들을 듣지 못하는거야!
-그들이 좋아하겠군!
just animals roaming on the ice.
- That's because you can't hear them.
They welcomed it!
자신들을 위해 누군가 싸우고 있다고 한다면 말이야.
-얼간이 같으니라고!
It's not as if they put up a fight.
- You idiot!
그들은 손에 자신들의 뇌를 가지고 태어나. 못봤어?
They're born with their brains
in their hands, don't you see?
그게 그들을 평화롭게 만드는거야,
그들은 그래야해,
That makes them peaceful,
they've got to be,
왜냐면 누구든 만나면 믿는 그런 생명체니까!
-오, 훌륭한데. / -고마워요.
cos a creature like that
would have to trust anyone it meets.
- Oh, nice one.
- Thank you!
이 시스템은 200년에 걸쳐 만들어진거다.
모두 우리가 이룬거지.
The system's worked for 200 years.
All we've got is a rogue batch.
하지만 오염된건 소독되어야겠지. 케스?
But the infection is about
to be sterilised. Mr Kess?
어느정도 진행됐나?
-산탄 준비 끝났습니다.
How do we stand?
- Canisters primed, sir.
열이 달궈지는 대로, 가스가
살포될것입니다.
As soon as the core heats up,
the gas is released.
200에 맞춰놓겠습니다.
카운트 시작됩니다.
Give it 200 marks...
and counting.
그들에게 가스를 살포할 생각이야?!
-가축처럼 죽이는거지.
- You're gonna gas them?!
- Kill the livestock.
고전적인 구제역 해결책은 오래전부터
사용되어오던 해결 방안이었지.
The classic foot-and-mouth solution
from the olden days.
여전히 사용되고 있고.
Still works.
[CHUCKLING]
[EERIE SINGING]
[SINGING CONTINUES]
죄송합니다만 한가지만
더 부탁드리겠습니다.
I'm sorry, if I could ask you one
more time, could all the Reps please
모두들 교육 스위트로 자리를 옮겨주세요.
-왜 지금 옮겨요? 여기 바는 공짜라고요!
come through to the
Education Suites.
Why move now?
It's a free bar!
모든 우드들은 뒤로 물러나,
식사 시간이야.
Could I ask all the Ood
to withdraw, it's feeding time.
오! 당신이 저것들을 화나게 했어요.
그냥 내버려 둬요!
Aw! You've upset them.
Leave them alone!
강조하겠다.
만약 우드 모두가 떠나지 않는다면..
I have to insist.
If all the Ood could please leave...
여러분, 일정이 바뀌었습니다.
비상용 탈출구로 향해주세요.
Ladies and gentlemen,
change of plan.
If you could leave
by the fire exits.
이거 사겠어!
다른 색깔도 제공되나보군.
I could sell this!
You could offer different colours.
아아악!
Aaargh!
아악!
Aargh!
They've gone insane, Miss,
they've gone mad, all of them!
저것들 모두 미쳤어요!
저것들 모두 돌았다고요, 모두요!
그냥 쏴버려요! 쏴서 죽여버려요!
Just shoot them! Shoot to kill!
[ALARM SOUNDS]
What the hell?
뭐야?
밖에서 무슨일이 일어나고 있는거야?
What's going on out there?
'긴급 상황. 긴급 상황.
모든 출구가 막혔습니다.'
'Emergency status. Emergency status.
All exits sealed.'
이건 혁명이야.
It's a revolution.
[BLEEPING]
돌아와! 날 이곳에서 꺼내줘!
Come back! Let me out of here!
아악!
Aargh!
어떻게 됐는지 말해봐.
밖의 세상에서 문제에 관한 보고는
없습니다. 아직은 이곳, 우드 천체뿐입니다.
No reports of trouble
off-world, sir,
it's still contained to the Ood-Sphere.
- We've got a public duty to stop it
우리는 이 상황이 더 퍼지기 전에
막아야할 사회적 의무가 있어.
무슨일이 일어난거야?
모든것이 당신이 원하는대로 됐지, 닥터.
의심할것도 없이 곧 이곳은 소독이 끝난후에
Everything you wanted.
No doubt there'll be a full police
investigation once this place
경찰조사로 가득차겠지. 난 자살행위따윈
하지 않아. 그래도 당신에게 우드의
인정정도는 남겨주고가지.
has been sterilised, so I can't risk
a bullet to the head.
I'll leave you to the
mercies of the Ood.
하지만 뭔가 더 있어,
안그래? 우리가 보지못한 무언가가 말이야!
-무슨 말이에요?
But there's something else,
isn't there? Something
we haven't seen!
What you mean?
생명체는 전뇌와 후뇌가 분리된상태로는 살수없어, 그건 불가능해. 뭔가가 더 있는거야.
A creature couldn't survive with a
separate fore brain and hind brain,
they'd be at war with themselves,
there's got to be a third element.
세번째 요소가 있는거라고.
-매우 영리하군!
- So clever! - It's got to be connected
to the red-eye, what is it?
그게 바로 레드-아이와 연관되어 있는거야,
그게 뭐지?
"그건" 얼마 안있어 사라지게 될거야.
"It" won't exist
for very much longer.
너의 우드나 실컷 즐기라고.
Enjoy your Ood.
얼른!
Come on!
- Dr Ryder. Warehouse 15.
- Well, what about THIS one?
레이더 박사. 15번 창고..
-저기, '저건'어쩌고요?
아냐. 넌 끝까지 변하지 않았어.
끝까지 충직했지.
No. You've not turned.
Faithful to the last.
가, 가서 너의 종족들에게 합류해,
네가 아직 그럴수 있을때 말이야.
Go, join your people,
while you still can.
가자.
Come on.
글쎄, 어떻게좀 해봐요!
당신 트릭같은거 잘하잖아요!
Well, do something!
You're the one with all the tricks!
당신이 후디니를 만났어야 했는데! (마술사)
-이 수갑들 엄청 좋은것들이군!
- You must've met Houdini!
- These are really good handcuffs!
오, 그거 다행이네요!
Oh, well I'm glad of that
내 말은, 하다못해
좋은거라도 하나 얻었으니 말이에요!
I mean, at least
we've got quality
[DOORS OPEN]
어..닥터, 도나, 친구.
-원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다.
Doctor, Donna - friends. The circle
must be broken. Doctor, Donna -
friends! The circle must be broken!
닥터, 도나, 친구!
-원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다!
Doctor, Donna, friends! The circle
must be broken! Friends, friends,
friends! The circle must be broken!
친구, 친구, 친구!
-원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다!
닥터, 도나, 친구!
-원은 반드시 파괴되어야 한다
-친구, 친구, 친구!
Doctor, Donna, friends!
The circle must be broken!
Friends, friends, friends!
닥터, 도나, 친구!
Doctor, Donna, friends!
친구!
-원은 반드시...!
Friends! The circle must...!
[EERIE SINGING]
닥터, 도나, 친구.
Doctor. Donna. Friends.
그래! 우리야! 친구! 오, 좋았어!
-그래, 이 남자랑, 나야!
Yes! That's us! Friends! Oh, yes!
안돼! 내버려둬.
No! Leave him.
그게 어디에 있는지 모르겠어!
그들이 어디로 갔는지 모르겠다고!
I don't know where it is!
I don't know where they've gone!
우리가 찾는게 뭔데요?
What are we looking for?
아마 지하에 있을거야, 둥굴이라던가 땅굴같이, 아니면...
Might be underground, like some
sort of cave, or a cavern, or...
'15번 창고, 문 개방합니다.'
'Warehouse 15. Door open.'
괜찮아?
All right?
언제나 선택권이 있어,
내 할아버지께서 이 계획을 세우셨지.
It's always been an option,
my grandfather drew up this plan.
이게 바로 집안이 운영하는 기업의
이점이라니까, 레이더 박사.
-하지만 저들을 철수시켜야 합니다.
That's the advantage of a family-run
business, Dr Ryder. The personal
touch. But we should evacuate.
만약 로켓 화물 창고만 확보한다면...
-필요없어! 우린 이게 있으니까.
- If we can get to the rocket sheds...
- No need! We've got this.
폭발 장비들.
이것들을 주변에 둘러놔.
Detonation packs.
Place them around the circumference.
우리가 폭파시켜버리는거야.
We're gonna blow it up.
죽는건 우드야.
This thing dies, so do the Ood.
[BLEEPING]
[SAD SINGING]
우드의 뇌야.
The Ood Brain.
이제야 모든게 이해가 가. 이게
잃어버린 링크, 세번째 요소야.
Now it all makes sense, that's the
missing link, the third element,
이 모든게 하나로 이어져.
전뇌, 후뇌, 그리고 이-
binding them together.
Fore brain, hind brain, and this -
텔레파시 센터가 말이야.
the telepathic centre.
이건 마음을 공유해서 노래로
모든 우드들을 연결시키는거야.
It's a shared mind,
connecting all the Ood in song.
화물칸, 언제나 화물칸에만
있으면 된다니까.
Cargo. I can always go into cargo.
내겐 로켓이 있어, 화물 창고도 있지.
작지만 가축도 필요없고 훨씬 다루기 쉬운
작은 기업도 있지.
I've got the rockets, I've got the
sheds. Smaller business, much more
manageable, without livestock.
그가 이 공간을 팠죠.
-저들이 지금 저걸 죽이려는 건가요?
- He's mined the area.
- They're gonna kill it?
그들은 이걸...2세기 전에 북쪽의 빙하
바로 밑에서 발견했지.
They found that...thing centuries
ago beneath the Northern Glacier.
저 탑들. -원을 만들고 있어요.
"원은 반드시 파괴되어야한다."
- Those pylons.
- In a circle.
- "The circle must be broken."
- Damping the telepathic field.
텔레파시의 진폭을 줄여, 우드에게
전해지는걸 200년동안 막은거야.
Stopping the Ood from connecting
for 200 years.
그리고 너, 우드 시그마, 네가 저들을 이곳으로 데려왔지. 기대 이상이군.
And you, Ood Sigma, you brought
them here. I expected better.
제 자리는 당신의 옆입니다.
하-하! 여전히 비굴하군.
Ha-ha! Still subservient.
좋은 우드야.
Good Ood.
만약 저기에 베리어같은게 있다면
어떻게 우드들이 텔레파시를 받고
폭동을 일으키기 시작한거죠?
If that barrier thing's in place,
how come the Ood started
breaking out?
아마도 몇세기동안 적응해가면서
잠재의식이 깨어난걸꺼야.
Maybe it's taken centuries to adapt.
The subconscious reaching out.
하지만 그 과정은 너무나 느렸어요.
촉진시켜줄 필요가 있었죠.
But the process was too slow.
Had to be accelerated.
당신은 내게 컨트롤에 접근할수있게
하지 말았어야 했어요. 할펜씨.
내가 베리어를 최소치로 낮췄죠.
You should never have given me
access to the controls, Mr Halpen.
I lowered the barrier to its minimum.
우드의 친구에요.
Friends Of The Ood, sir.
나를 회사에 침투시키는데
10년이나 걸렸죠.
It's taken me ten years
to infiltrate the company.
그리고 결국 성공했어요.
And I succeeded.
그래. 그래. 네가 한짓이군.
Yes. Yes, you did.
아악!
Aargh!
당신이...저 사람을 죽였어!
You... murdered him!
잘도 알아차리는군, 그래. 진저.
(머리가 붉은 사람을 뜻하는 말)
Very observant, Ginger.
자, 그럼...
Now, then...
전에 아무도 안쏴봤다고는 말못하지.
can't say I've ever shot
anyone before.
그렇게 할거라고도 말못하고.
Can't say I'm gonna like it.
하지만 오늘은 확실히 평범한 날이
아니잖아, 안그래? 움직이지마...
But it's not exactly a normal day,
is it? Still...
마실것을 드릴까요?
Would you like a drink, sir?
내 생각에 머리가 빠지는건 현재로서는 별로 중요한 문제가 아니야, 고마워.
I think hair loss is the least
of my problems right now, thanks.
한잔 드시죠.
-만약...만약 네가 계속 내 그들 앞에
서 있는다면,
- Please have a drink, sir. - If... If
you're going to stand in their way,
너도 쏴버리겠어.
I'll shoot you too.
드세요.
Please have a drink, sir.
너..너...내게 독약을 먹인거냐?
Have... Have you... poisoned me?
자연적인 우드는 절대 살인을 하지 않습니다.
-그럼 저건 성분이 뭔데?
- Natural Ood must never kill, sir.
- What is that stuff?
우드-이식 조직를 띄운
생물학적 혼합물입니다.
-그게 대체 무슨 소리야?!
Ood-graft suspended
in a biological compound, sir.
What the hell does THAT mean?!
오, 이런...
-뭔지 말해!
- Oh, dear...
- Tell me!
잠재의식이라는건 재밌는거야.
모든 양상을 가지고있다가
Funny thing, the subconscious.
Takes all sorts of shapes.
그게 복수를 위해 레드-아이의 형태로
나타난거야. 분노에 미쳐 날뛰는 우드로 말이야.
It came out in the
red-eye as revenge.
Came out in the rabid Ood as anger.
그리고 여기엔 인내심있게 기다린
형태도 있지.
And then there was patience.
모든 지능과 자비가 우드 시그마에게
집중된거야.
All that intelligence and mercy,
focused on Ood Sigma.
머리 빠지는건 좀 어때? 할펜?
How's that hair loss, Mr Halpen?
대체 무슨짓을 한거야?
What have you done?
오, 그들이 아주 오랫동안 너를 위해
준비한것이지.
Oh, they've been preparing you for a
very long time.
이제 당신은 우드 뇌 옆에 서 있으니,
자, 할펜. 들리나?
Now you're standing next to the Ood
Brain. Mr Halpen, can you hear it?
들어봐.
Listen...
[EERIE SINGING]
대체 무슨짓을...?
What have you...?
나는...!
I'm...not...!
[HE DROPS GUN]
우드들이..우드들이 저 사람을
우드로 변하게 만든거에요?
They... They turned him
into an Ood?!
그래.
-저사람, 우드잖아요.
He's an Ood.
나도 눈치챘어.
I noticed.
저 자는 이제 우드족이 되었습니다.
He has become Oodkind.
그리고 우리가 저 자를 보살필겁니다.
And we will take care of him.
섬뜩해요,
당신과 함께 있으면 나는 더이상 어떤것이
It's weird,
being with you, I can't tell what's
right and what's wrong any more.
옳은것 이고 어떤것이 그릇된것인지
말할수 없어요.
그게 더 나아.
사람들은 누구나 어느정도는 할펜처럼
될 수 있는 경향이 있거든.
It's better that way.
People who know for certain
tend to be like Mr Halpen.
오!
[BEEPING]
Ooh!
훨씬 낫군, 그럼 이제...
That's better. And now...
시그마, 내게 이걸 끝내버릴
영광을 주시겠습니까?
Sigma, would you allow me the honour?
그건 당신이 해야할 일입니다, 닥터.
-오, 좋았어!
- It is yours, Doctor.
- Oh, yes!
200년동안 억눌려왔어.
Stifled for 200 years.
하지만 더 이상은 아니야!
원은 파괴됐어, 이제 우드는 노래할수 있어!
But not any more. The circle
is broken, the Ood can sing.
[JOYOUS SINGING]
나도 들려요!
I can hear it!
[SINGING CONTINUES]
메세지는 사라졌어.
The message has gone out.
이 노래는 은하계를 가로질러 모두가 들을수 있도록 울려퍼졌어.
That song resonated across the
galaxies, everyone heard it.
로켓이 그들을 도로 데려올거야.
The rockets are bringing them back,
우드는 집으로 돌아오고 있어.
the Ood are coming home.
우리 모두 당신들께 감사하고 있습니다.
닥터, 도나.
We thank you, Doctor-Donna.
우드족의 친구들.
Friends of Oodkind.
그럼, 이제 어떻게 하실건가요?
이곳에 머무실건가요?
And what of you now, will you stay?
당신을 위해 노래할 방은 많이 있습니다.
There is room in the song for you.
오, 나는...
Oh, I've...
말하자면 나도 내 노래가 있어.
고마워.
sort of got a song of my own, thanks.
제 생각엔 당신의 노래는 곧 끝이 날것같습니다.
I think your song must end soon.
무슨뜻이지?
-모든 노래는 끝이나기 마련입니다.
- Meaning?
- Every song must end.
그렇지.
Yeah.
음, 당신은 어때?
Erm, what about you?
아직도 집에 가고싶어?
-아니요.
You still want to go home? No.
-확실히 아니에요.
Definitely not.
그럼, 우린 이만 갈께.
-이 노래를 가져가세요. / -그럴께요.
Then, we'll be off.
- Take this song with you.
- We will.
항상.
Always.
그리고 이걸 알아두세요, 닥터-도나.
우린 절대 당신들을 잊지 않을거에요.
And know this, Doctor-Donna.
You will never be forgotten.
우리의 아이들도 닥터-도나의
노래를 부를거에요.
Our children will sing
of the Doctor-Donna,
그리고 우리의 아이들의 아이들도,
바람과 빙하, 눈은 항상 당신의 이름을
전할거에요. 영원히.
and our children's children,
and the wind and the ice and the
snow will carry your names, forever.
닥터, 나 마사에요,
내가 당신을 지구로 돌아오게 할거에요.
어제 52명이 동일한 사건으로 죽었습니다.
세상을 바로 가로지르는
11개의 타임존이 있습니다.
아트모스가 외계인이라고 생각해?
우리의 일은 가능성을 조사하는 겁니다.
당신 누구야?
-나는 손타란 함대의 스탈 장군이다.
침입자다!
-블루 스카이 작전 시작!
그게 당신이 그녀에게 한짓이에요?
그녀를 군인으로 바꾼거?
이게 뭐야?! -손타론!
죽음의 얼굴을 들여다봐라!
한글자막-JIN. jhj124@naver.com (장혜진)
무단배포하지 말아주세요.